A Guide to the Papers of Ann Beattie
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ann Beattie 1976-1990
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10414-t,-u
This collection consists of 39 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited 1990 March 26 and 1990 June 21.
Scope and Content Information
The papers contain manuscripts (setting copy), galley and page proofs of Chilly scenes of winter and Distortions; and draft and proofed manuscript of Picturing Will.
Also manuscripts or proofs of various short stories and articles including "Alex Katz," "Installation #6," "Mine," "People, places and things that will appear / that will never appear in my writing," "Performances," "San Miguel de Allende," "Scott McDowell," "Summer people," "Taking hold," "The wedding cake in the middle of the road," "Windy day at the resevoir."
There are also uncorrected page proofs of advance copies of 22 books sent to her for review including Against joie de vivre, Bad girls, The bridesmaid, Close company, Color of light, The courtyard, The distant lover, Dogeaters a novel, and Grace.
Also The innocent, The irreversible decline of Eddie Socket, Latecomers, The music room, My one and only, Onion, Physical culture, Three thousand dollars stories, Triangulation, We find ourselves in moontown stories, The women in her dreams, and Where you once belonged.
Contents List
- Manuscripts of Novels
  - Alex Katz by Ann Beattie, w/comments by [David] Wiegand [1987], TMs (Box 1)
  - At Twelve: Portraits of Young Women by Sally Mann, "Introduction" by Ann Beattie [ca. 1988], TMs (Box 1)
  - Chilly Scenes of Winter by Ann Beattie 1976, TMs (Setting Copy) (Box 1)
    329 pages (2 folders)
  - Chilly Scenes of Winter by Ann Beattie 1976, Galley Proof (Box 1)
    (Reader's Galleys)
  - Chilly Scenes of Winter by Ann Beattie 1976, Page Proof (Box 1)
    (Confirmation Proofs)
  - Distortions by Ann Beattie 1976, TMs (Setting Copy) (Box 2)
    337 pages (2 folders)
  - Distortions by Ann Beattie 1976, Galley Proof (Box 2)
  - Distortions by Ann Beattie 1976, Page Proof (Box 1)
  - Picturing Will by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 2)
    240 pages, Original Draft w/author's corrections
  - Picturing Will by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 3)
    237 pages, Author's Copy of Proofed Manuscript, w/author's corrections and notations
  - Picturing Will Part I "Mother" by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 3)
  - Picturing Will Part II "Father" by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 3)
  - Picturing Will Part I "Mother" by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 3)
    w/author's corrections
  - Picturing Will Part II "Father" by Ann Beattie [1989?], TMs (Box 3)
- Manuscripts of Short Stories & Articles
  - Travel Article re the Crawford Notch area of the White Mountains in New England Monthly by Ann Beattie n.d., Galley Proof (Box 3)
  - "Installation #6" by Ann Beattie n.d., AMs (Box 3)
    5 pages
  - Life Magazine Article by Ann Beattie n.d., 2 TMs (Box 3)
    w/annotated corrections by the author
  - "Mine" by Ann Beattie n.d., TMsS & Galleys (Box 3)
    (4 items)
  - Article re the National Museum of Women in the Arts by Ann Beattie n.d., TMs (Box 4)
  - "People, Places, and Things That Will Appear/That Will Never Appear in My Writing" in Story Quarterly by Ann Beattie 1985, Printed (Box 4)
  - "Performances" by Ann Beattie n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
    w/author's corrections and additions
  - "San Miguel de Allende" by Ann Beattie n.d., TMs & Galleys (Box 4)
  - "Scott McDowell" by Ann Beattie n.d., TMsS (Box 4)
    4 pages
  - "Summer People" in The New Yorker by Ann Beattie 1984, TMs (Box 4)
  - "Taking Hold" in Fiction Network by Ann Beattie 1986, Printed (Box 4)
  - "The Wedding Cake in the Middle of the Road" by Ann Beattie n.d., TMsS (Box 4)
  - "Windy Day at the Reservoir" by Ann Beattie n.d., 2 TMs (Box 4)
  - Untitled Short Stories by Ann Beattie n.d., 11 TMs (Box 4)
- Letter
  - Tom Durwood, Ariel Books, to Ann Beattie 1987 Dec 14, TLS (Box 4)
    [asks her permission for his small press, The Kipling Press, to publish a library edition of Spectacles in the same format as that of The Owl] 1 page
- Manuscripts of Other Writers
  - Against Joie De Vivre by Phillip Lopate 1989, Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 4)
  - Bad Girls by Mary Flanagan 1984, Bound Uncorrected Proof (Box 4)
  - The Bridesmade by Ruth Rendell 1989, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 4)
  - Close Company edited by Christine Park and Caroline Heaton 1989, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 4)
  - Color of Light by Alan Cheuse [1990?], TMs (Box 4)
    Bound Typescript, 445 p.
  - The Courtyard by Arkady Lvov 1988, Uncorrected Bound Page Proof (Box 5)
  - The Distant Lover by Christoph Hein, translated by Krishna Winston 1989, Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 5)
  - Dogeaters A Novel by Jessica Hagedorn 1990, Advance Reader's Galleys (Box 5)
  - Forehead Writing and Art Journal [1989], Printed (Box 5)
  - Grace by Maggie Gee [post 1986], Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - The Innocent by Ian McEwan 1990, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - The Irreversible Decline of Eddie Socket A Novel by John Weir 1989, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - Latecomers by Anita Brookner 1988, Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 5)
  - The Music Room by Dennis McFarland 1990, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - My One and Only by Ellie McGrath 1989, Uncorrected Bound Galleys (Box 5)
  - Onion by Kate Braestrup 1990, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - Physical Culture by Hillary Johnson 1989, Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 5)
  - Three Thousand Dollar Stories by David Lipsky 1989, Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 1989)
  - Triangulation by Jack Stephens 1989, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 5)
  - We Find Ourselves in Moontown Stories by Jay Gummerman 1989, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 6)
  - The Women in Her Dreams by Candace Denning 1988, Uncorrected Page Proof (Box 6)
  - Where You Once Belonged by Kent Haruf [1990?], TMs (Box 6)
  - Where You Once Belonged by Kent Haruf [1990], Advance Uncorrected Proof (Box 6)